#### 中文简历

========

张凯朝(男)

出生年月: 1982年5月 出生地点: 广东省普宁市 现居住地: 广东省广州市 移动电话: 13502460825

E-mail: zhangkaizhao@gmail.com

#### 求职意向

-----

包括并不局限于:研发工程师、高级研发工程师包括并不局限于:广州、深圳、汕头、揭阳、普宁

#### 职业概述

-----

自 2005 年毕业于华南理工大学机械工程及自动化专业,从事机械行业工作大概三年,于 2008 年开始转向计算机程序设计工作,主要使用 Python 语言从事 web 开发,熟练工作于 GNU/Linux 环境下。

### 工作经历

-----

- 2015,05 ~ 2015,10:广州七乐康药业连锁有限公司 (广州)

职位: 开发工程师

工作内容:隶属广州电商平台开发,主要职责是 Python 开发团队的技术指导等。先后参与的项目:负责商品质检文件管理系统后端开发,参与大白云诊之用药助手子项目后端开发,负责OFC(订单履约中心)初步架构设计与骨架搭建,库存系统库存同步后端开发。主要使用 Python 语言,主要使用 Django, celery 等。

- 2014,06 ~ 2015,01: 广东彩惠智能科技有限公司 (广州)

职位:高级开发工程师

工作内容: 主要负责互联网彩票代购系统(彩乐透项目)的后台开发。

- 2011,05 ~ 2014,01: 广州远云网络科技有限公司 (广州)

职位: 开发工程师

工作内容: 前期主要负责 Syncbox 产品的 webserver 后台的开发和维护, Syncbox 产品 Linux 客户端的维护,以及相应的 DDNS 服务器端和客户端的后期维护。后期主要负责路由器产品 WIT-FII 公共网站的架构及实现,路由器产品桌面客户端的开发。

补充信息:公司前名为:广州脱兔计算机科技有限公司。

- 2010,05 ~ 2011,05: 广州网融网络技术有限公司 (广州)

职位: 开发工程师

工作内容: 主要负责自动升级后台(基于 Google Omaha 项目)开发,文件同步服务端及客户端的原型开发,证联项目的前期技术调研和原型开发( OpenID/OAuth ),服务器及其他工作、项目相关管理系统的部署管理等。主要使用 Python 语言,主要使用 Tornado/wxPython/MongoDB 等。

- 2008,09 ~ 2009,12: 上海润普网络信息技术有限责任公司 (广州)

职位: 开发工程师

工作内容: 主要参与 everydo 各产品的前端和后台开发,协助产品的部署和运营等。主要使用 Python 和 Zope 3 等。

- 2006,04 ~ 2008,07: 汕头超声显示器有限公司 (汕头)

职位:设备工程师

工作内容:维护维修的各种生产设备,设计和完善各种相关配件、夹具等。主要使用设备维护维修工具以及AutoCAD/SolidWorks 等设计工具。

#### 工作能力

-----

- 熟练掌握 Python 语言及其标准库和常见的 Python 第三方库、开发框架及服务器等
- 熟悉 GNU/Linux 环境,特别是 Debian/Ubuntu, Fedora, Arch Linux, Gentoo 等
- 比较熟悉 MySQL 关系型数据库,和 Redis 等 key-value 缓存和存储

- 熟悉 HTML, CSS, JavaScript 等前端开发技术
- 熟练使用 Vim 及各种 UNIX 工具等进行开发
- 比较熟悉 Git 等版本控制系统

#### 教育经历

-----

- 2001/09-2005/07: 华南理工大学 本科 机械工程及自动化 工学学士
- 1998/09-2001/07: 汕头市金山中学 高中 - 1995/09-1998/07: 普宁市洪冶中学 初中

#### 语言能力

-----

- 英语: CET4 - 普通话: 良好 - 潮州话: 母语

#### 项目经验

\_\_\_\_\_

2014,06 ~ 2015,01: 彩乐透公司: 广东彩惠智能科技有限公司

描述: 互联网彩票代购系统。

职责:后台开发。

业绩:增加各种新功能比如虚拟货币体系、在线活动等,完善已有功能比如提款、下单支付、出票流程、后台各种管理功能等,改善系统架构、代码质量等。

技术: 主要使用 Python 语言,使用 Flask/SQLAlchemy/MySQL 等。

- 2013,06 ~ 2014,01: 路由器产品 WIT-FII 的公共网站

公司:广州远云网络科技有限公司

描述: 路由器产品 WIT-FII 的公共网站,包括账户及路由器管理、服务接口、中转服务、在线商店等。

职责:架构及实现。

业绩:运行正常,为 iOS 客户端和 Android 客户端提供的各种接口、中转服务正常。在线商店实现了支付宝即时到帐接口,可正常购买产品。

技术: 主要使用 Python 语言, 主要使用 gevent/WebOb/Jinja2/WTForms/SQLAlchemy/Redis 等。

- 2011,05 ~ 2013,06: Syncbox 产品的 webserver

公司:广州远云网络科技有限公司

描述:家庭私有存储服务的 web 服务器端,提供 web 页面供浏览、控制管理,提供 web 接口供移动终端客户端使用。

职责:开发包括各种文件(包括图片/PDF/Office/音频/视频/文本等)的预览图/缩略图的获取生成存取及文件元数据获取,推送文件到 Dropbox/Google Drive/SkyDrive/金山快盘/酷盘,维护服务接口。

业绩:为 web 页面、iOS 和 Android 客户端提供了预览图/缩略图服务。改善了代码组织、质量。增加了文档。

技术: 主要使用 Python 语言,主要使用 Tornado/Kyoto Cabinet/Berkeley DB 等。

#### 链接

-----

#### 个人相关

- https://www.zhangkaizhao.com

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/zhangkaizhao

## 工作相关

- http://www.clt500.com

- https://www.witfii.com/index.html

http://www.syncbox.cn

- http://www.everydo.com

- ...

- -

# ENGLISH RESUME

Name: Kaizhao Zhang

Gender: Male

Birthplace: Puning city, Guangdong province, China Residence: Guangzhou city, Guangdong province, China

Mobile: 086-13502460825

E-mail: zhangkaizhao@gmail.com

Job objective

-----

Including but not limited to: Developer Engineer, Senior Development Engineer Including but not limited to: Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Shantou, Jieyang, Puning

Summary

-----

Graduated from the South China University of Technology in Mechanical Engineering and Automation in 2005. As a mechanical engineer especially equipment engineer for about three years. Then begin to be a computer programmer in 2008. Mainly using Python language in web development(front end, back end), skilled working in GNU/Linux distribution environment.

# Work experience

\_\_\_\_\_

- 2014,06 ~ 2014,12: Guangdong Caihui Technologies Co.,Ltd. (Guangzhou) Senior Development Engineer

Working on development of internet lottery purcharsing agent system.

Using Python language. Using Flask/SQLAlchemy, etc.

- May,2011 - Jan,2014: Guangzhou Farcloud Network Technologies Co.,Ltd. (Guangzhou) Development Engineer

Early days, working on development(generating and accessing the preview and thumbnails images and metadata of various files including image files/PDF files/Office files/audio files/video files/text files. pushing files to Dropbox/Google Drive/SkyDrive/Jinshan Kuaipan/Kanbox. etc.) and maintenance(service API, etc.) of Syncbox webserver, maintenance of Syncbox Client for Linux, and maintenance of related DDNS server and client. etc.

Later period, as the author of public web application for WIT-FII Router(Account/Router management, service API, web gateway service, online shop(including the integration of Alipay create\_direct\_pay\_by\_user payment API), etc), and the developer of Desktop Client for WIT-FII Router, etc. (Note: WIT-FII Router product has not been published to public yet.)

Using Python language. Early days using Tornado/Kyoto Cabinet/Berkeley DB, etc. Later period using gevent/WebOb/Jinja2/WTForms/SQLAlchemy/Redis/PyQt5, etc.

May,2010 - May,2011: Guangzhou G4B Technologies Co.,Ltd. (Guangzhou)
Development Engineer

Working on autoupdate server developement. File synchronization server and client prototype development. Ubuntu Server and other work related software management.

Using Python language.

- Sep,2008 - Dec,2009: Zopen Technologies Co.,Ltd. (Guangzhou)

Development Engineer

Working on front-end and back-end development of everydo products. Ubuntu server deployment, etc.

Using Python language and Zope 3, etc.

Apr,2006 - Jul,2008: Shantou Goworld Display Co.,Ltd. (Shantou)
Equipment Engineer

Production machines maintenance. Design and repair fixtures of the machines, etc.

Using repair tools and AutoCAD/SolidWorks design tools, etc.

## Education

-----

- Sep,2001 Jul,2005: South China University of Technology Bachelor of engineering Mechanical Engineering and Automatizaion
- Sep,1998 Jul,2001: Shantou Jinshan School Senior high school
- Sep,1995 Jul,1998: Puning Hongye School Junior high school

## Skills

\_ \_ \_ \_ \_

- Python language and Python standard library, third party libraries, web frameworks and servers
- GNU/Linux. e.g. Debian/Ubuntu, Fedora, Arch Linux, Gentoo, etc
- Vim
- Git
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, etc

## Links

\_ \_ \_ \_

## Working related

- http://www.clt500.com
- https://www.witfii.com/index.html
- http://www.isyncbox.com
- http://www.everydo.com
- ...

# Personal related

- https://bitbucket.org/zhangkaizhao
- https://github.com/metalman
- http://www.douban.com/people/halfcool/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/zhangkaizhao

- -

Last modified on Apr.30,2015